André VIDELA

Personal Data

PLACE AND DATE OF BIRTH: Switzerland | 20 August 1991

Address: Rue pré-du-marché 9B, 1004 Lausanne, Switzerland

PHONE: +41 79 822 0541

EMAIL: andre.videla@gmail.com

Вю

Fascinated by programming languages, I seek excellence, correctness and beauty in code. Lots of experiences in game development taught me to mix pragmatism and elegance. My deepest interests lie in type systems and programming language theory and design.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Current Oct. 2016	Software Engineer at Sicpa, Lausanne $Mobile\ engineer\ for\ iOS$ Designed, developed and maintained internal and public APIs and libraries for iOS. Developed and maintained small and medium scale mobile applications.	Swift, Obj-C
July 2016	Summer camp teacher at TECHSPARK, Lausanne Taught basic programming to kids from 7 to 17 using Swift. Subjects include functions, flow control, loops and side effect all of which were implemented in an unsupervised personal project by the students.	Swift
JULY 2015-SEPT 2015	Internship at Kabotip, Tokyo (Remote) Developed micro-services in Clojure for the Kabotip platform. Namely the mobile notification service and the automatic moderation tool for user comments.	Clojure, Redis
2013-2014	Volunteer developer at Dischan, (Remote) Worked on Android ports and helped with QA	Java

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016 Interrupted Bachelor in Computer Science at EPFL, Lausanne 131 credits

2007 - 2012 Maturité Gymnasiale

option principale Physique et Application des Math option secondaire Introduction à la programmation

CERTIFICATES AND PROJECTS

May 2017	Introduction to Logic by Stanford University on Coursera. statement of accomplishment	
July 2016	Delta-zone, a color-based puzzle game made for the Epic Game Jam	Unity and C#
Mar. 2016	Designed and implemented a music description language for Arcaea (Remote)	C++, Javascript
Feb. 2016	Start Hack: Medical feedback app for iOS	Swift
Sept 2015	${\bf Hacker spaces}$ for iOS, an App that allows you to track hacker space openings across the world	Swift
Apr. 2015	Facebook Hackaton @EPFL. A project to take care of a connected plant.	Swift
May 2015	Helped implement parsing tools, real time event handling and UI for T-Aiko A rhythm game on android and iOS (Remote)	Java
June 2014	Vertical 2D Side scroller shooter for Epic Game Jam	Swift
Mar. 2014	A geolocalised music app for Android for Facebook Hackathon @EPFL $$	Java
Jan. 2014	Horizontal 2D Side scroller shooter for Global Game Jam	Scala

LANGUAGES

French: Mothertongue

ENGLISH: Fluent

SPANISH: Good speaker
JAPANESE: Basic knowledge

Programming Languages

Mastery Swift, Java
Excellent Scala, JS, Obj-C
Intermediate Haskell, Clojure, C++, C, C#
Beginner Idris, Coq, Rust

Interests and Activities

- VIDEO GAMES continuously teach me new ways of interacting within a team, handling hard situations and keeping the right mindset in highly competitive settings.
- MATH keeps me engaged in the latest developments in programming language research and theory. It allows me to find elegant and correct solutions to hard problems daily.